<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-22T16:20:39-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">./dev blog - StoryTime Productions</title><subtitle>Welcome to the StoryTime Productions ./dev blog! Behind the screen insights from our game development journey in Montreal, Quebec.  We create immersive Unity games spanning horror, sci-fi, and arcade genres.</subtitle><author><name>StoryTime Productions</name></author><entry><title type="html">From Montreal to the World: The StoryTime Productions Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/studio/montreal/indie%20development/montreal-storytime-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From Montreal to the World: The StoryTime Productions Journey" /><published>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/studio/montreal/indie%20development/montreal-storytime-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/studio/montreal/indie%20development/montreal-storytime-journey/"><![CDATA[<p>Bonjour from the beautiful city of Montreal! 🍁 As we launch our official dev blog, we wanted to share the story behind StoryTime Productions and what drives us to create immersive gaming experiences from Canada’s cultural hub.</p>

<h2 id="our-montreal-roots">Our Montreal Roots</h2>

<div class="montreal-accent">
Montreal isn't just our location—it's our inspiration. This vibrant, bilingual city with its rich cultural tapestry, harsh winters, and thriving creative scene shapes everything we do. From the metro tunnels that inspired Prochaine Station to the diverse communities that inform our game narratives, Montreal is woven into the DNA of our studio.
</div>

<h3 id="why-montreal-for-game-development">Why Montreal for Game Development?</h3>

<p>Living and working in Montreal provides unique advantages for indie game developers:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Cultural Diversity</strong>: Our bilingual environment influences how we approach localization and accessibility</li>
  <li><strong>Government Support</strong>: Quebec’s robust support for creative industries and tech startups</li>
  <li><strong>Educational Excellence</strong>: Access to world-class universities like McGill, Concordia, and UQAM</li>
  <li><strong>Affordable Living</strong>: Lower costs of living compared to other major tech hubs</li>
  <li><strong>Creative Community</strong>: A thriving indie game scene with regular meetups and game jams</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="our-development-philosophy">Our Development Philosophy</h2>

<div class="game-dev-highlight">
We believe great games come from authentic experiences. Our team of students and creators from diverse backgrounds—engineering, computational arts, multimedia—brings fresh perspectives to every project. We're not just making games; we're crafting interactive stories that resonate with players worldwide.
</div>

<h3 id="our-game-portfolio">Our Game Portfolio</h3>

<p>Each of our projects reflects different aspects of our creative vision:</p>

<h4 id="-prochaine-station">🚇 Prochaine Station</h4>
<p><strong>Genre</strong>: <span class="unity-badge">Horror</span> <span class="unity-badge">Psychological</span><br />
<strong>Status</strong>: Coming June 2025</p>

<p>Our psychological horror adventure transforms Montreal’s familiar metro system into an unsettling journey. Players experience seemingly mundane daily tasks that gradually become increasingly bizarre and disturbing.</p>

<p><strong>Montreal Connection</strong>: Using actual metro station layouts and architectural elements that Montrealers will recognize, then subverting them into something uncanny.</p>

<h4 id="-argonassault">🚀 ArgonAssault</h4>
<p><strong>Genre</strong>: <span class="unity-badge">Sci-Fi</span> <span class="unity-badge">Action</span><br />
<strong>Status</strong>: Released August 2024</p>

<p>A 3D space combat experience where players pilot ships through challenging environments while engaging in precision laser battles.</p>

<p><strong>Technical Focus</strong>: Showcasing our Unity expertise with complex physics systems and smooth control mechanics.</p>

<h4 id="-zombie-runner">🧟 Zombie Runner</h4>
<p><strong>Genre</strong>: <span class="unity-badge">Survival</span> <span class="unity-badge">Action</span><br />
<strong>Status</strong>: Coming June 2025</p>

<p>Fast-paced survival action where players defend against zombie hordes using strategic weapon selection and environmental awareness.</p>

<p><strong>Design Philosophy</strong>: Balancing intense action with tactical decision-making.</p>

<h4 id="-realmrush">🏰 RealmRush</h4>
<p><strong>Genre</strong>: <span class="unity-badge">Strategy</span> <span class="unity-badge">Defense</span><br />
<strong>Status</strong>: Released August 2024</p>

<p>A medieval-themed tower defense game featuring strategic crossbow placement and resource management.</p>

<p><strong>Educational Value</strong>: Exploring advanced data structures and AI pathfinding algorithms.</p>

<h2 id="technical-excellence-through-diversity">Technical Excellence Through Diversity</h2>

<p>Our team’s diverse academic backgrounds create a unique development environment:</p>

<h3 id="engineering-perspective">Engineering Perspective</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Optimization Focus</strong>: Performance-first approach to game development</li>
  <li><strong>System Architecture</strong>: Scalable, maintainable code structures</li>
  <li><strong>Problem-Solving</strong>: Creative solutions to complex technical challenges</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="computational-arts-vision">Computational Arts Vision</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Interactive Design</strong>: User experience and player engagement</li>
  <li><strong>Visual Storytelling</strong>: Communicating narrative through environmental design</li>
  <li><strong>Creative Technology</strong>: Pushing Unity’s capabilities for artistic expression</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="multimedia-expertise">Multimedia Expertise</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Audio Design</strong>: Immersive soundscapes and reactive audio systems</li>
  <li><strong>Visual Effects</strong>: Shader development and particle systems</li>
  <li><strong>Content Creation</strong>: Asset pipeline optimization and workflow automation</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="community-and-collaboration">Community and Collaboration</h2>

<p>Montreal’s game development community has been instrumental in our growth:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Montreal Independent Games Festival (MIGS)</strong>: Showcasing and learning from industry veterans</li>
  <li><strong>Unity User Group Montreal</strong>: Technical knowledge sharing and networking</li>
  <li><strong>Game Jams</strong>: Rapid prototyping and creative experimentation</li>
  <li><strong>University Partnerships</strong>: Collaborating with local academic institutions</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="looking-forward-2025-and-beyond">Looking Forward: 2025 and Beyond</h2>

<p>As we enter 2025, StoryTime Productions is positioned for exciting growth:</p>

<h3 id="upcoming-releases">Upcoming Releases</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Prochaine Station</strong> (June 2025): Our most ambitious psychological horror project</li>
  <li><strong>Zombie Runner</strong> (June 2025): Refined survival action gameplay</li>
  <li><strong>Untitled Project</strong>: A secret project exploring new genres 🤫</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="technical-goals">Technical Goals</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Mobile Expansion</strong>: Bringing our PC experiences to iOS and Android</li>
  <li><strong>VR Exploration</strong>: Investigating immersive technologies for future projects</li>
  <li><strong>Web Distribution</strong>: WebGL optimization for browser-based gaming</li>
  <li><strong>Cross-Platform Play</strong>: Connecting players across different devices</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="community-building">Community Building</h3>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Open Development</strong>: Sharing more behind-the-scenes content through this blog</li>
  <li><strong>Educational Content</strong>: Unity tutorials and optimization guides</li>
  <li><strong>Local Engagement</strong>: Supporting Montreal’s indie game community</li>
  <li><strong>International Reach</strong>: Connecting with global indie developers</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="join-our-journey">Join Our Journey</h2>

<p>Whether you’re a fellow game developer, a student exploring the industry, or simply someone who loves great games, we invite you to follow our journey. This blog will be our window into the creative process, sharing:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Technical Insights</strong>: Code solutions, optimization techniques, and Unity tips</li>
  <li><strong>Creative Process</strong>: Design decisions, art direction, and narrative development</li>
  <li><strong>Montreal Life</strong>: How our city influences our games and development culture</li>
  <li><strong>Industry Perspectives</strong>: Thoughts on indie development trends and challenges</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="connect-with-us">Connect With Us</h3>

<ul>
  <li>🌐 <strong>Website</strong>: <a href="https://storytime-productions.github.io">storytime-productions.github.io</a></li>
  <li>💻 <strong>GitHub</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/StoryTime-Productions">StoryTime-Productions</a></li>
  <li>📧 <strong>Email</strong>: <a href="mailto:brommitment@gmail.com">brommitment@gmail.com</a></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<div class="game-dev-highlight">
From all of us at StoryTime Productions, merci beaucoup for joining us on this adventure. Whether you're in Montreal, somewhere else in Canada, or anywhere around the world—we're excited to share our stories with you.
</div>

<p><em>Happy gaming, and stay warm!</em> ❄️🎮<br />
<em>– The StoryTime Productions Team</em></p>

<p><em>P.S. Keep an eye on our GitHub for upcoming Unity tutorials and code samples from our projects!</em></p>]]></content><author><name>StoryTime Productions</name></author><category term="studio" /><category term="montreal" /><category term="indie development" /><category term="storytime productions" /><category term="montreal" /><category term="indie games" /><category term="unity" /><category term="game development" /><category term="canada" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bonjour from the beautiful city of Montreal! 🍁 As we launch our official dev blog, we wanted to share the story behind StoryTime Productions and what drives us to create immersive gaming experiences from Canada’s cultural hub.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to StoryTime Productions ./dev blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/announcement/studio/my-first-blog-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to StoryTime Productions ./dev blog" /><published>2024-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/announcement/studio/my-first-blog-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/announcement/studio/my-first-blog-post/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the StoryTime Productions ./dev blog! We’re thrilled to launch this platform where we’ll be sharing insights from our game development journey here in Montreal, Quebec.</p>

<h2 id="who-we-are">Who We Are</h2>

<p>StoryTime Productions is a passionate collective of game developers, engineers, and multimedia specialists based in the beautiful city of Montreal. We’re students and creators who grew up with a love for PC and console gaming, and now we’re channeling that passion into creating our own interactive experiences.</p>

<h2 id="what-youll-find-here">What You’ll Find Here</h2>

<p>This blog will serve as our development diary and technical journal. Expect to find:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Development Insights</strong>: Behind-the-scenes looks at our Unity game development process</li>
  <li><strong>Technical Deep Dives</strong>: Solutions to challenges we encounter while building games</li>
  <li><strong>Creative Process</strong>: How we approach game design, art, and storytelling</li>
  <li><strong>Project Updates</strong>: Progress reports on our current and upcoming games</li>
  <li><strong>Industry Reflections</strong>: Our thoughts on game development trends and techniques</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="our-current-projects">Our Current Projects</h2>

<p>We’re actively working on several exciting projects:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Prochaine Station</strong>: A psychological horror adventure set in a metro environment (Coming June 2025)</li>
  <li><strong>Zombie Runner</strong>: A survival game featuring zombie hordes and strategic combat (Coming June 2025)</li>
  <li>Various arcade and experimental projects</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="join-our-journey">Join Our Journey</h2>

<p>Whether you’re a fellow game developer, a gaming enthusiast, or just curious about what goes on behind the screen, we invite you to follow along as we document our adventures in game development.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more posts about our technical challenges, creative breakthroughs, and the unique perspective of developing games from Montreal!</p>

<p><em>Happy coding,</em><br />
<em>The StoryTime Productions Team</em> 🎮</p>]]></content><author><name>StoryTime Productions</name></author><category term="announcement" /><category term="studio" /><category term="welcome" /><category term="game development" /><category term="unity" /><category term="montreal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the StoryTime Productions ./dev blog! We’re thrilled to launch this platform where we’ll be sharing insights from our game development journey here in Montreal, Quebec.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Prochaine Station: Horror Game Design in Unity</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/game%20development/unity/horror/another-interesting-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Prochaine Station: Horror Game Design in Unity" /><published>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/game%20development/unity/horror/another-interesting-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/game%20development/unity/horror/another-interesting-post/"><![CDATA[<p>One of our most ambitious projects at StoryTime Productions is <strong>Prochaine Station</strong>, a psychological horror adventure that transforms the familiar Montreal metro system into something unsettling and mysterious.</p>

<h2 id="the-concept">The Concept</h2>

<div class="game-dev-highlight">
Prochaine Station takes players through seemingly mundane daily tasks that gradually become increasingly bizarre and unsettling. The game explores psychological horror through environmental storytelling and subtle narrative shifts.
</div>

<h2 id="design-philosophy">Design Philosophy</h2>

<p>Our approach to horror game design focuses on:</p>

<h3 id="1-atmospheric-tension">1. <strong>Atmospheric Tension</strong></h3>
<p>Rather than relying on jump scares, we build tension through:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Gradual environmental changes</li>
  <li>Subtle audio cues and ambient soundscapes</li>
  <li>Lighting that shifts imperceptibly over time</li>
  <li>Familiar spaces that slowly become unfamiliar</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="2-montreal-metro-inspiration">2. <strong>Montreal Metro Inspiration</strong></h3>
<p>Living in Montreal, we’re intimately familiar with the metro system. This local knowledge allows us to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Recreate authentic station layouts and atmospheres</li>
  <li>Subvert player expectations of familiar spaces</li>
  <li>Incorporate unique architectural elements of Montreal’s underground</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="3-unity-implementation-challenges">3. <strong>Unity Implementation Challenges</strong></h3>

<p>Working in Unity, we’ve encountered several interesting technical challenges:</p>

<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Example: Dynamic lighting system for psychological effects</span>
<span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">PsychologicalLighting</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">MonoBehaviour</span> 
<span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">SerializeField</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="k">private</span> <span class="n">Light</span><span class="p">[]</span> <span class="n">ambientLights</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">SerializeField</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="k">private</span> <span class="n">AnimationCurve</span> <span class="n">intensityCurve</span><span class="p">;</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">Update</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="kt">float</span> <span class="n">timeProgression</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">GameManager</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Instance</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">GetNormalizedGameTime</span><span class="p">();</span>
        <span class="kt">float</span> <span class="n">targetIntensity</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">intensityCurve</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Evaluate</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">timeProgression</span><span class="p">);</span>
        
        <span class="k">foreach</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Light</span> <span class="n">light</span> <span class="k">in</span> <span class="n">ambientLights</span><span class="p">)</span> 
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="n">light</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">intensity</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">Mathf</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Lerp</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">light</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">intensity</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">targetIntensity</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">Time</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">deltaTime</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="development-insights">Development Insights</h2>

<h3 id="audio-design">Audio Design</h3>
<p>The soundscape is crucial for psychological horror. We’re layering:</p>
<ul>
  <li><span class="unity-badge">Metro</span> Authentic metro station ambience</li>
  <li><span class="unity-badge">Horror</span> Subtle distortions and anomalies</li>
  <li><span class="unity-badge">Dynamic</span> Reactive audio that responds to player behavior</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="level-design">Level Design</h3>
<p>Each station in our game serves as both a familiar space and a psychological canvas:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Berri-UQAM</strong>: The central hub with branching narratives</li>
  <li><strong>Mont-Royal</strong>: Claustrophobic tunnels and echoing spaces</li>
  <li><strong>Atwater</strong>: Industrial atmosphere with mechanical undertones</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>

<p>We’re targeting a <strong>June 2025</strong> release for Prochaine Station. In upcoming posts, we’ll dive deeper into:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shader development for atmospheric effects</li>
  <li>Narrative branching systems</li>
  <li>Performance optimization for mobile platforms</li>
  <li>Localization challenges (French/English)</li>
</ul>

<p>The intersection of local culture, technical innovation, and psychological storytelling makes this project uniquely exciting for our Montreal-based team.</p>

<p><em>More development insights coming soon!</em><br />
<em>– The StoryTime Productions Team</em> 🚇</p>]]></content><author><name>StoryTime Productions</name></author><category term="game development" /><category term="unity" /><category term="horror" /><category term="prochaine station" /><category term="unity engine" /><category term="horror game design" /><category term="psychological thriller" /><category term="montreal metro" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[One of our most ambitious projects at StoryTime Productions is Prochaine Station, a psychological horror adventure that transforms the familiar Montreal metro system into something unsettling and mysterious.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Unity Optimization Techniques for Montreal Indie Developers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/technical/unity/optimization/exploring-new-ideas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unity Optimization Techniques for Montreal Indie Developers" /><published>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/technical/unity/optimization/exploring-new-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/technical/unity/optimization/exploring-new-ideas/"><![CDATA[<p>As an indie game development studio in Montreal, performance optimization is crucial for our Unity projects. With limited resources, we need to ensure our games run smoothly across various platforms while maintaining visual quality.</p>

<h2 id="our-optimization-journey">Our Optimization Journey</h2>

<div class="montreal-accent">
Working from Montreal gives us a unique perspective on optimization - we need to consider both high-end gaming setups and mobile devices to reach our diverse Canadian and international audience.
</div>

<h2 id="key-optimization-strategies">Key Optimization Strategies</h2>

<h3 id="1-texture-compression-and-atlasing">1. <strong>Texture Compression and Atlasing</strong></h3>

<p>One of our most effective techniques involves intelligent texture management:</p>

<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Custom texture streaming for our horror games</span>
<span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">OptimizedTextureManager</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">MonoBehaviour</span> 
<span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">System</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Serializable</span><span class="p">]</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">TextureSettings</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="k">public</span> <span class="n">Texture2D</span> <span class="n">texture</span><span class="p">;</span>
        <span class="k">public</span> <span class="n">TextureFormat</span> <span class="n">mobileFormat</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">TextureFormat</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">ASTC_6x6</span><span class="p">;</span>
        <span class="k">public</span> <span class="n">TextureFormat</span> <span class="n">desktopFormat</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">TextureFormat</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DXT5</span><span class="p">;</span>
        <span class="k">public</span> <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">maxSize</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="m">1024</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">SerializeField</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="k">private</span> <span class="n">TextureSettings</span><span class="p">[]</span> <span class="n">gameTextures</span><span class="p">;</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">Start</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nf">OptimizeTexturesForPlatform</span><span class="p">();</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">OptimizeTexturesForPlatform</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="n">TextureFormat</span> <span class="n">targetFormat</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">Application</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">isMobilePlatform</span> <span class="p">?</span> 
            <span class="n">TextureFormat</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">ASTC_6x6</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">TextureFormat</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">DXT5</span><span class="p">;</span>
            
        <span class="k">foreach</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">var</span> <span class="n">setting</span> <span class="k">in</span> <span class="n">gameTextures</span><span class="p">)</span> 
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="nf">ApplyCompressionSettings</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">setting</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">texture</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">targetFormat</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">setting</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">maxSize</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h3 id="2-lod-systems-for-complex-environments">2. <strong>LOD Systems for Complex Environments</strong></h3>

<p>For games like <strong>Prochaine Station</strong>, we implement custom LOD systems:</p>

<div class="game-dev-highlight">
<ul>
<li><span class="unity-badge">LOD 0</span> Full detail metro stations (0-15m)</li>
<li><span class="unity-badge">LOD 1</span> Reduced geometry (15-30m)</li>
<li><span class="unity-badge">LOD 2</span> Simplified textures (30-50m)</li>
<li><span class="unity-badge">LOD 3</span> Billboard/imposter (50m+)</li>
</ul>
</div>

<h3 id="3-memory-pool-management">3. <strong>Memory Pool Management</strong></h3>

<p>For action games like <strong>ArgonAssault</strong>, object pooling is essential:</p>

<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Laser projectile pooling system</span>
<span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">LaserPool</span> <span class="p">:</span> <span class="n">MonoBehaviour</span> 
<span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">SerializeField</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="k">private</span> <span class="n">GameObject</span> <span class="n">laserPrefab</span><span class="p">;</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">SerializeField</span><span class="p">]</span> <span class="k">private</span> <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">poolSize</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="m">100</span><span class="p">;</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="n">Queue</span><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">GameObject</span><span class="p">&gt;</span> <span class="n">laserPool</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="k">new</span> <span class="n">Queue</span><span class="p">&lt;</span><span class="n">GameObject</span><span class="p">&gt;();</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">Start</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="nf">InitializePool</span><span class="p">();</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="k">private</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">InitializePool</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="k">for</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="m">0</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="p">&lt;</span> <span class="n">poolSize</span><span class="p">;</span> <span class="n">i</span><span class="p">++)</span> 
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="n">GameObject</span> <span class="n">laser</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="nf">Instantiate</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">laserPrefab</span><span class="p">);</span>
            <span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">SetActive</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">false</span><span class="p">);</span>
            <span class="n">laserPool</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Enqueue</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="n">GameObject</span> <span class="nf">GetLaser</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">laserPool</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Count</span> <span class="p">&gt;</span> <span class="m">0</span><span class="p">)</span> 
        <span class="p">{</span>
            <span class="n">GameObject</span> <span class="n">laser</span> <span class="p">=</span> <span class="n">laserPool</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Dequeue</span><span class="p">();</span>
            <span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">SetActive</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">true</span><span class="p">);</span>
            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">;</span>
        <span class="p">}</span>
        
        <span class="c1">// Fallback: create new instance</span>
        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="nf">Instantiate</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">laserPrefab</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">ReturnLaser</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">GameObject</span> <span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">)</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">SetActive</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="k">false</span><span class="p">);</span>
        <span class="n">laserPool</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Enqueue</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">laser</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="montreal-specific-considerations">Montreal-Specific Considerations</h2>

<h3 id="cold-weather-testing">Cold Weather Testing</h3>
<p>Montreal winters provide natural stress testing opportunities:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Battery performance on mobile devices in cold conditions</li>
  <li>Thermal throttling behavior</li>
  <li>Screen responsiveness in low temperatures</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="bilingual-ui-optimization">Bilingual UI Optimization</h3>
<p>Supporting French and English requires:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Dynamic text sizing systems</li>
  <li>Font atlas optimization for accented characters</li>
  <li>Layout flexibility for different text lengths</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="local-community-feedback">Local Community Feedback</h3>
<p>Our Montreal gaming community provides valuable feedback:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Unity user group meetups at Concordia University</li>
  <li>Local game jams and testing sessions</li>
  <li>Diverse hardware testing across economic demographics</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="performance-metrics-that-matter">Performance Metrics That Matter</h2>

<p>For our games, we target:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>60 FPS</strong> on modern smartphones (iPhone 12+, Galaxy S21+)</li>
  <li><strong>30 FPS minimum</strong> on older devices (iPhone X, Galaxy S10)</li>
  <li><strong>&lt; 2GB RAM</strong> usage on mobile platforms</li>
  <li><strong>&lt; 5-second</strong> loading times between levels</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="tools-we-use">Tools We Use</h2>

<h3 id="unity-profiler-integration">Unity Profiler Integration</h3>
<div class="language-csharp highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="c1">// Custom profiling for our games</span>
<span class="cp">#if UNITY_EDITOR || DEVELOPMENT_BUILD
</span><span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">static</span> <span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">StoryTimeProfiler</span> 
<span class="p">{</span>
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">System</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Diagnostics</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Conditional</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"UNITY_EDITOR"</span><span class="p">)]</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">static</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">BeginSample</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="kt">string</span> <span class="n">sampleName</span><span class="p">)</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="n">UnityEngine</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Profiling</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Profiler</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">BeginSample</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">$"StoryTime.</span><span class="p">{</span><span class="n">sampleName</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="s">"</span><span class="p">);</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
    
    <span class="p">[</span><span class="n">System</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Diagnostics</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">Conditional</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">"UNITY_EDITOR"</span><span class="p">)]</span>
    <span class="k">public</span> <span class="k">static</span> <span class="k">void</span> <span class="nf">EndSample</span><span class="p">()</span> 
    <span class="p">{</span>
        <span class="n">UnityEngine</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Profiling</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="n">Profiler</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nf">EndSample</span><span class="p">();</span>
    <span class="p">}</span>
<span class="p">}</span>
<span class="cp">#endif
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="lessons-learned">Lessons Learned</h2>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Profile Early, Profile Often</strong>: Don’t wait until the end of development</li>
  <li><strong>Target Platform First</strong>: Optimize for your lowest-spec target device</li>
  <li><strong>Community Testing</strong>: Local Montreal developers provide honest feedback</li>
  <li><strong>Seasonal Considerations</strong>: Account for Quebec’s extreme temperature variations</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="whats-next">What’s Next</h2>

<p>In upcoming posts, we’ll explore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Custom shader optimization for horror atmosphere</li>
  <li>AI pathfinding optimization for zombie hordes</li>
  <li>Cross-platform input handling</li>
  <li>WebGL deployment strategies</li>
</ul>

<p>Performance optimization is an ongoing journey, especially for indie studios. Every frame counts when you’re trying to create immersive experiences on a budget!</p>

<p><em>Keep optimizing,</em><br />
<em>The StoryTime Productions Team</em> ⚡</p>]]></content><author><name>StoryTime Productions</name></author><category term="technical" /><category term="unity" /><category term="optimization" /><category term="unity engine" /><category term="performance" /><category term="mobile development" /><category term="indie game development" /><category term="montreal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As an indie game development studio in Montreal, performance optimization is crucial for our Unity projects. With limited resources, we need to ensure our games run smoothly across various platforms while maintaining visual quality.]]></summary></entry></feed>